Guide to the Something Borrowed Something Blue Records, 1997-2014 UA.31.07.0014
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Something Borrowed Something Blue records
1997-2014
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Something Borrowed Something Blue
UA.31.07.0014
1.5 Linear Feet
Something Borrowed Something Blue is a co-ed Christian a cappella group at Duke University. The Something Borrowed Something Blue records include materials documenting the group's activities, beliefs, and music selection and performance. Also included are copies of several albums released by SBSB, and captures of the group's website from 2010-2012.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Biographical / Historical
Something Borrowed Something Blue is a co-ed Christian a cappella group at Duke University. Originally founded in 1969 as the Jesus Christ Power and Light Company, the group changed their name in 1998 to Something Borrowed and Something Blue, and is called both Borrowed and Blue and SBSB.
SBSB has a purpose "to glorify God, primarily through music," as stated in the group's constitution. It takes its name from the traditional poem of having a bride wear something old, something new, something borrowed, and something blue on her wedding day, and refers to the depiction of the church as the bride of Christ throughout the New Testament of the Bible. The group consists mostly of undergraduate men and women, gives several performances throughout the academic year, and engages in social and outreach activities, including an annual spring break service trip. The group has also released several albums.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Use of audiotapes and videotapes from this collection requires the creation of reference copies. Reference copies for some materials may have been made, and if a reference copy exists, it is noted in this finding aid. To arrange for the creation of reference copies of other items, please contact University Archives staff. Although these recordings are now stored in a stable environment, their condition and playback quality is unknown.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Something Borrowed Something Blue records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2015.
Related Materials
Out of the Blue records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Pitchforks of Duke University Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Collection Overview
The Something Borrowed Something Blue records consist of materials related to the activities, performances, album recording and releases, and music selection of the a cappella group Something Borrowed Something Blue. Included in the collection are audition sheets, song licensing information, fundraising proposals, member comments, publicity photographs, and a number of copies of music selections, some with notes, for the group's performances, among other materials. Also included are several albums released by the group, including two from the Jesus Christ Power and Light Company and several from SBSB, and captures of the group's website from 2010-2012.
Choral singing; Choruses (Mixed voices), Unaccompanied; Music -- Religious aspects.; Duke University -- Songs and music; Duke University -- Students; Something Borrowed Something Blue
- Audition materials, 2005-2014 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bible study/spiritual, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- CD requests, CD marketing, 1999, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Concert programs and tickets, 2001-2012 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Constitution, positions survey, schedules, scripts, notes, 1999-2011 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 2002-2008 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Funding information, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Fundraising, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Funding proposals, 2008, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- General manager's binder, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- General manager's binder, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Gospel Jam/other a cappella contacts, 1997-2000 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- License information for Unseen, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Licenses and production information for REcreation, Something Old Something New, 1999-2002 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Personal envelope questions, group survey questions, skills survey, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Philosophy, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Publicity materials, 2007, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Sheet music and lyrics (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Sheet music A-C (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Sheet music D-H (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Sheet music I-K (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Sheet music L-P (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Sheet music R-T (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Sheet music W-Y (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Web Archives, 2010-2012
- Jesus Christ Power and Light 1989-1990, audiocassette (Box 1, Audio-cassette UA31070014-CS-0001)
- Jesus Christ Power and Light 1990-1991, audiocassette (Box 1, Audio-cassette UA31070014-CS-0002)
- Jesus Christ Power and Light 1989-1990, use copy CD, compact disc (Box 1, Audio-disc UA31070014-CD-0001)
- Jesus Christ Power and Light 1990-1991, use copy CD, compact disc (Box 1, Audio-disc UA31070014-CD-0002)
- Something Old Something New, 1997-1998; compact disc (Box 1, Audio-disc UA31070014-CD-0003)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Use of audiotapes and videotapes from this collection requires the creation of reference copies.
- From Ashes to Glory, 2009-2011; compact disc (Box 1, Audio-disc UA31070014-CD-0004)
- Ascending, 2012; compact disc (Box 1, Audio-disc UA31070014-CD-0005)
- Lost and Found, 2014; compact disc (Box 1, Audio-disc UA31070014-CD-0006)